M. BERTAN ULUSOY

Senior Solution Architect

A Computer Engineer with three years of self-study in artificial intelligence on 10+ years of proven software developer skills. A practitioner who, with a passion for research, updates himself according to new technologies and algorithms, and transforms existing ones into daily practice.



EXPERIENCE

Ankara, Turkey
Nov 2020 - Present

Senior Solution Architect

Allylab.co

The Unation is an American event management and ticketing platform. The platform allows anyone to create, share, find and attend events under the desired topic.

- Prepared a Time-Series Analysis to forecast of event creation density by end-users
- Necessary support was given to Data Engineers by creating queries in MongoDB
- To ensure that the new features we bring to the platform are deployed in accordance with the existing structure and to correct the errors.
- An application has been written to manage data with pyMongo which is MongoDB Python driver

Ankara, Turkey
Nov 2019 - Oct 2020

Senior Software Developer

DAS Archiving Document and Management System

DAS is a document archiving and management company. It produces high value-added solutions by developing document-based products on Microsoft platforms with its R&D studies.

- R&D project work was carried out on the personal data protection law.
- The in-file discovery feature has been developed in targeted folders
- Image extractions were handled with OCR technology.
 Relational database studies were carried out
- Software and relational database architectural studies were carried out

Ankara, Turkey
Oct 2015 - Mar 2019

Senior Software Developer

Onur Engineering

ONUR Engineering is a leading engineering and systems integration provider in Turkey. ONUR has been providing value-added services in both defence and civil communication fields.

Projects named HERON(unmanned aerial vehicle),
 ANKA(unmanned aerial vehicle), HSTA, DHMI which are IP based voice communication systems were developed and maintained.

Ankara, Turkey Apr 2015 - Oct 2015

Senior Software Developer

Ayder Tourism

Ayder Tourism is a company that develops congress and organizational management systems software.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email

bertan_ulusoy@yahoo.com

Phone

(533)7797026

SKILLS

- Python
- Django
- Matplotlib
- Artificial Neural Networks
- PyTorch
- Keras
- PostgreSQL
- SQL
- MongoDB
- Scikit-Learn
- Tensorflow

LANGUAGES

English

Intermediate

- Congress and organization registration web software was developed
- New features have been added to the congress and organization management system software, and the existing features have been maintained.

Ankara, Turkey *Jul 2013 - Apr 2015*

Software Developer

Nanosens

Nanosens is a software company that creates solutions for academicians.

Projects named AES(Academic Inventory System),
 ABEP(Academic Units Activity Measurement Software), and
 MicroNIR Sensor project were developed and maintained.

Ankara, Turkey Nov 2011 - May 2013

Software Developer

Solvent

The solvent is a software company that develops business on the hospital information management system in the health sector

 Hospital Information System software projects were developed and maintained.

Ankara, Turkey Sep 2009 - Jul 2011

Software Developer

Mega Industry Control Systems

The company serves refineries and petroleum storage terminals, specializing in management, measurement and control of road tanker filling, vessel loading and pipeline operations.

 Analysis, test, installation and implementation of software to be integrated into the internal and external automation system using Microsoft .Net platform were applied.

EDUCATION

Ankara, Turkey

Oct 2003 - Feb 2008

Ankara, Turkey Sep 1997 - Jun 2002

Computer Engineering

Ahmet Yesevi University

Computer Technology and Programming

Bilkent University

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Neural Networks and Deep Learning -

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/H2PBP6F3Y9WV

Intermediate Python for Data Science -

https://www.datacamp.com/statement-of-accomplishment/course/f99ae49277dc60f59baf2f572096ca27b52c6b8d

Intro to Python for Data Science -

https://www.datacamp.com/statement-of-accomplishment/course/6cf8e2133b270328eb51cd25997d1e1f2b679f66

Supervised Learning with Scikit-learn

https://www.datacamp.com/statement-of-accomplishment/course/c28b7752a77c1e6c4804a6b0d8beb20f72a26473